Guide to the Full Frame Archive Collection, 1998-2017 RL.00424
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Full Frame Film Festival, 2010
  - Surviving Hitler: A Love Story (2010)
    A wartime love story provides a fresh perspective on life under Germany's Third Reich. As a confident, bubbly teenager, Jutta is surprised to learn that she is half-Jewish, launching her resistance to the Nazis. She falls in love with Helmuth, an injured German soldier. Disillusioned, Helmuth joins the unsuccessful Valkyrie plot to assassinate Hitler. Jutta, Helmuth, and her parents are relentlessly pursued by the Nazi machine and separately imprisoned. Incredibly, all four survive and are reunited at the end of the war. Jutta eloquently narrates her own story, illustrated with original 8mm footage (shot by Helmuth) and rare archival footage.
    - Preservation tape master, HDCam, TRT 66:00 (Box 7)
    - DVD master, TRT 66:00 (Box 8)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Book of Miri (2009)
    Director: Katrine Philp
    Producer: Rasmus Abrahamsen
    TRT: 29:00
    Miri, a Korean adoptee who grew up and lives in Sweden is a self-described loner. She comes home from her job as a librarian every evening and invents funky, creative outfits for her fashion blog-her main outlet for personal expression and social interaction. In words and artistic photography, she shares her life with her readers, from mundane details to musings on the psychological consequences of international adoption. With no narration and little spoken dialogue, the film is a visually poetic portrait of Miri.
    In Swedish with English subtitles.
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 29:00 (Box 7)
    - DVD master, TRT 27:00 (Box 8)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - 12th and Delaware (2010)
    Directors: Heidi Ewing and Rachel Grady
    Producers: Sheila Nevins and Sara Bernstein
    An intersection in Fort Pierce, Florida, provides a microcosm of one of America's most controversial ideological wars. An abortion clinic named A Woman's World sits across the street from the pro-life Pregnancy Care Center. Pregnant teenagers and women often mistake the pro-life center for the abortion clinic, and are patiently and persuasively counseled by its staff, often with deceptive tactics, to keep their pregnancies. Meanwhile, the medical staff of the clinic try to counsel patience to make their own choices and to perform their work under siege; pro-life protesters walk the sidewalk in front of the clinic day and night, hectoring patients, and the physician must arrive and leave from work anonymously, concealed under a sheet, to protect his own life. Turning a non-judgmental lens on both camps, Grady and Ewing use the extraordinary access they gained to practitioners, protestors, and patients to show us a conflict with seemingly no possible resolution.
    - Preservation tape master, HDCam, TRT 80:00 (Box 7)
    - DVD master, TRT 80:00 (Box 8)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Festival materials, 2010
    - Programs and postcards, 2010 (Box 6, Box 17)
    - Lanyard, patches, baseball cap, t-shirt, tote bags, 2010; 2 bags (Box 17)
    - Poster, 2010 (Box 19)
- Full Frame Film Festival, 2011
  - Buck (2011)
    Director: Cindy Meehl
    Producers: Julie Goldman
    This portrait of horse trainer Buck Brannaman takes the animal-human relationship as a metaphor for facing the challenges of life. Buck was a professional rope trick performer by the age of six, exploited and violently abused by his father. Today, he is known for his compassionate approach to working with horses, eschewing violence and punishment in favor of a respect for the way horses think (he is one of the inspirations for the novel and film The Horse Whisperer). The film follows Buck on the road; he travels nine months out of the year teaching clinics where he "helps horses with people problems," coaching riders and starting (rather than "breaking") young horses.
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 1 of 5, 1584 ft. (Reel 131)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 2 of 5, 1584 ft. (Reel 132)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 3 of 5, 1584 ft. (Reel 133)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 4 of 5, 1584 ft. (Reel 134)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 5 of 5, 1584 ft. (Reel 135)
  - One Night in Kernersville (2011)
    Director: Rodrigo Dorfman
    Producer: Rodrigo Dorfman
    Awards won: Full Frame Jury Award for Best Short
    TRT: 20:00
    Jazz bassist John Brown anticipates his long-awaited day in Mitch Easter's Kernersville, North Carolina, recording studio. Sound and image of Brown's big band recording session comments musically and visually on Brown's insights on music's power to communicate joy and friendship.
    - Preservation tape master, HDCam, TRT 20:00 (Box 10)
    - DVD master, TRT 20:00 (Box 8)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - How to Die in Oregon (2011)
    - Preservation tape master, HDCam (Box 7)
    - DVD master (Box 8)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Auk Nr. 8 (2010)
    English title: Pit No. 8
    Director: Marianna Kaat
    Producers: Marianna Kaat and Olena Fetisova
    Country: Estonia and the Ukraine
    Awards won: Charles E. Guggenheim Emerging Artist Award and The Nicholas School Environmental Award
    Once a thriving coal-mining area, the Donetsk region of the Ukraine is now peppered with makeshift illegal mines, excavated in demolished buildings, parks and backyards. Economic hardship has driven even children to work in the mines. Marianna Kaat follows the trials of fifteen-year old Yura and his two sisters. Living apart from their alcoholic parents, they rely on Yura to mine for eight to twelve hours a day to support them. He cannot consistently attend school, though he dreams of someday earning certification as a baker to run a café. Ironically, his grandfather was a powerful Soviet coal plant director. The film follows the children for over a year as they struggle to pay their bills and stay together.
    - Preservation tape master, HDCam, TRT 94:00 (Box 10)
    - DVD master, TRT 94:00 (Box 8)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - We Still Live Here / Âs Nutayuneân (2010)
    TRT: 56:00
    This is the story of the revival of the language of the Wampanoag people of New England. All speakers of the language had died out when in 1994 Jessie Little Doe, a Wampanoag social worker began to wonder if it could be recovered. With M.I.T. linguist Ken Hale, with whom she earned a Master's degree, she and other linguists pieced the language together from old documents and related Native American languages. Through community-wide efforts among the Aquinnah and Mashpee Wampanoag, the language is being spoken again, and Jessie's young daughter is the first native speaker of Wampanoag in more than a hundred years.
    - Preservation tape master, HDCam, TRT 56:00 (Box 10)
    - DVD master, TRT 56:00 (Box 8)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Caretaker for the Lord (2010)
    Director: Jane McAllister
    Producer: Jane McAllister
    Country: Scotland
    TRT: 17:00
    St. Luke's and St. Andrew's Parish Church in Glasgow's East End, with a congregation of only 26, is slated for closure by the Church of Scotland; the new minister bitterly preaches that it should be left to die. This verité film captures with a light touch the activities of the still-vibrant community within the church's walls, from line dancing to yoga to lunch, anchored by the labors of Tommy Healy, the building's caretaker.
    - Preservation tape master, DigiBeta, TRT 17:00 (Box 10)
    - DVD master, TRT 17:00 (Box 8)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Festival materials, 2011
    - Programs, 2011 (Box 6, Box 18)
    - Tote bags, t-shirts, 2011 (Box 17, Box 18)
- Full Frame Film Festival programs, 2012-2017
  - Program, 2012 (Box 6)
  - Programs, 2013-2017 (Box 18)